<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on Rob Bevan</title>
    <link>/categories/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on Rob Bevan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2006 08:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Moon/Golf/Bowie image before Xmas and win an iPod Shuffle</title>
      <link>/post/2006-11-25-create-a-moongolfbowie-image-before-xmas-and-win-an-ipod-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2006 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-11-25-create-a-moongolfbowie-image-before-xmas-and-win-an-ipod-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>To celebrate the success of the PlayTime event and continue Tim Wright&amp;#8217;s mission to play golf on the moon (with David Bowie), XPT is offering a iPod Shuffle to the person who comes up with the best photographic simulation of a particular aspect of the the 30-year plan.

By concretising events and situations in a series of manipulated images, we are making the whole project more real, more achievable. Simulation=Solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlayTime: Playing with Pictures</title>
      <link>/post/2006-11-22-playtime-playing-with-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2006 10:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-11-22-playtime-playing-with-pictures/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks on, I&amp;#8217;m finally getting around to uploading my slides from my PlayTime presentation, Playing with Pictures (it&amp;#8217;s a 20MB+ PDF file, exported from Keynote). I was intending to annotate these so that they&amp;#8217;d make more sense to someone who weren&amp;#8217;t at my session, but I&amp;#8217;m not sure when, if ever, I&amp;#8217;ll do this.

This gist of it however was this: Photo manipulation has always had a bit of a bad name, and even today we&amp;#8217;re still worried that adding, removing or modifying parts of a photographic image detract from photography&amp;#8217;s perceived ability to show us the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al Gore on Climate Change</title>
      <link>/post/2006-03-29-al-gore-on-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2006 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-03-29-al-gore-on-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>I was invited today by one of my clients &amp;#8211; The Climate Group &amp;#8211; to watch Al Gore give his presentation on Climate Change at the bfi London IMAX Cinema. Gore&amp;#8217;s presentation is pretty well covered elsewhere, so I&amp;#8217;m not even going to try and summarise it here (it was too dark to take notes and besides I&amp;#8217;m a lousy note-taker anyway). Suffice to say for someone who has a reputation for being boring, he&amp;#8217;s both funny and extremely passionate about our need to find a common moral purpose to deal with this &amp;#8220;planetary emergency&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Web Apps</title>
      <link>/post/2006-02-23-the-future-of-web-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 00:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-02-23-the-future-of-web-apps/</guid>
      <description>Like most of the UK&amp;#8217;s web development community I was at the Carson Workshops Future of Web Apps summit a couple of weeks ago. A couple of highlights for me were Tom Coates&amp;#8217; wonderfully lucid and entertaining synthesis of all things Web 2.0 (see also Jeremy Zawodny&amp;#8217;s annotations of Tom&amp;#8217;s slides) and David Heinemeier Hansson&amp;#8217;s Ruby on Rails &amp;#8216;sermon&amp;#8217;. Although I&amp;#8217;ve been working with Rails intermittently for at least eighteen months I&amp;#8217;ve never seen David speak and it had never really occurred to me before just how Scandinavian Rails is: minimal, beautifully designed and good for the soul.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>