<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Film on Rob Bevan</title>
    <link>/categories/film/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Film on Rob Bevan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2006 18:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/film/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For Your Consideration</title>
      <link>/post/2006-02-19-for-your-consideration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2006 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-02-19-for-your-consideration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bafta.org/&#34;&gt;Orange British Academy Film Awards&lt;/a&gt; take place tonight. For the record, here&amp;#8217;s the complete list of screeners dispatched to BAFTA members this year. Considering we were &lt;span class=&#34;hilite&#34;&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; sent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinea.com/sv300.html&#34;&gt;Cinea players&lt;/a&gt; even before last year&amp;#8217;s awards &amp;#8211; and how quickly unencrypted movies &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.toptechnews.com/story.xhtml?story_id=11300002Q0PZ&#34;&gt;started appearing on the web&lt;/a&gt; this year &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s curious that only about 20% of DVDs were encrypted (using Cinea&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cinea.com/awardscreeners.html&#34;&gt;S-VIEW Award Consideration Screener Program&lt;/a&gt;). Mind you, from the point of view of the studios, encryption can obviously backfire, as those co-ordinating Munich&amp;#8217;s BAFTA campaign discovered when 5000 totally unplayable discs were shipped out, &lt;a href=&#34;http://film.guardian.co.uk/news/story/0,,1683771,00.html&#34;&gt;a story&lt;/a&gt; that even made the front page of The Guardian. &lt;strong&gt;Munich&lt;/strong&gt; is the only movie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oscars.org/78academyawards/noms.html&#34;&gt;Oscar-nominated for best picture&lt;/a&gt; not also on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bafta.org/site/page287.html&#34;&gt;BAFTA shortlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of the bunch for me was Fernando Meirelles&amp;#8217; &lt;strong&gt;The Constant Gardener&lt;/strong&gt;, (conversely the only BAFTA-nominated movie not also up for best picture in the US) a near-perfect exercise in direction, performance and cinematography and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kottke.org/06/02/syriana&#34;&gt;hyperlink movies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Syriana&lt;/strong&gt; (good) and &lt;strong&gt;Crash&lt;/strong&gt; (better). Joaquin Phoenix and Reese Witherspoon were both outstanding in Johnny Cash biopic &lt;strong&gt;Walk the Line&lt;/strong&gt;, as was Felicity Huffman&amp;#8217;s extraordinary woman-plays-man-becoming-woman performance in &lt;strong&gt;Transamerica&lt;/strong&gt; (but sadly overlooked by BAFTA) and you can&amp;#8217;t fail to enjoy Piers Brosnan&amp;#8217;s trashing of his Bond history in &lt;strong&gt;The Matador&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shame not to see Cronenberg&amp;#8217;s &lt;strong&gt;A History of Violence&lt;/strong&gt; in the running for more than adapted screenplay (although William Hurt is Oscar-nominated for his supporting role) or the hilarious &lt;strong&gt;A Cock &amp;amp; Bull Story&lt;/strong&gt;, the endlessly prolific Michael Winterbottom&amp;#8217;s attempt to film &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/exec/obidos/ASIN/0375761195/robbish-21/&#34;&gt;Tristam Shandy&lt;/a&gt; and a role call of current British comedy stars. Deservedly ignored in the UK though was Woody Allen&amp;#8217;s &lt;strong&gt;Match Point&lt;/strong&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dadblog.co.uk/archives/2006/01/woody_allen_and.html&#34;&gt;Lloyd Shepherd&amp;#8217;s post&lt;/a&gt; on why we Brits think this movie is &amp;#8216;lamentable&amp;#8217;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>